A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774
1936-2005
1950s-1990s
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA739D
54.72 Cubic Feet Document boxes 385-529.
Conditions Governing Access
Catalogued Reports are open for research with select reports restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement
The Catalogued Reports are arranged numerically by an arbitrary call number assigned during cataloging, from 1 to approximately 20,000.
Scope and Contents
The Ford Foundation's Catalogued Reports collection includes policy and programming documents, program evaluations, and periodic program status reports produced by Foundation officers and staff, as well as consultants and grantees. Some published material produced by Ford Foundation grants is also included in the collection. The collection also includes some of the Ford Foundation's own publications, such as the Annual Reports and newsletters.
- The Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic: information for program specialists and staff (Reports 009287), 1965 (Box 385)
  Program Name
  Overseas Division/Near East and Africa
  Extent
  38 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Consultants -- Egypt -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Technical assistance -- Egypt; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Personnel management; Endowments -- Egypt -- Evaluation
- The Ford Foundation in the United Arab Republic (Reports 009288), 1970 (Box 385)
  Abstract/Summary
  "A report prepared for Mr. Abdel Moneim El-Naggar, Ministry of Foreign Affairs." --T.p.
  International Division/Middle East and Africa
  1 v.; var. pag. -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- Egypt -- Evaluation; Technical assistance -- Egypt
- Report on the mission to the Sudan, March 19-22 (Reports 009289), 1973 (Box 385)
  12 p.
  The Sudan -- Education
- Administrative policies and procedures (Reports 009290), 1969 (Box 385)
  Related Grant Number
  06290135
  Related Grantee Name
  Foundation-Administered Project (FAP)
  Related Grant Purpose
  Program specialists and consultants for public administration in Saudi Arabia.
  37 p. -- 28 cm.
  Public administration -- Saudi Arabia; Technical assistance -- Saudi Arabia
- Library handbook (Reports 009291), 1973 (Box 385)
  Administration/Library
  40 p.
  Library administration -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.
- Original report of Iverson-Moyer et al mission --Near East, 1951 or 1952. (Reports 009292) (Box 385)
  Overseas Division
  100 p.
  Economic development -- Middle East; Education, Higher -- Middle East; Vocational education -- Middle East; Rural development -- Middle East
- Administrative policies and procedures applicable to Ford Foundation professional staff in the U.A.R. (Reports 009293), 1969 (Box 385)
  32 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Consultants -- Egypt -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Technical assistance -- Egypt
- Notes on T. Keenen reporting trip (Oct. 17, 1962-January 8, 1963): The Middle East (Reports 009294) (Box 385)
  various pagings.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Middle East
- Terminal evaluation: National School of Administration, Algeria (Reports 009295), 1974 (Box 386)
  Memo to Robert H. Edwards and Wilbert J. LeMelle, dated April 18, 1974.
  4 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Algeria; Civil service -- Study and teaching -- Algeria; Technical assistance -- Algeria; Endowments -- Algeria -- Evaluation
- Terminal evaluation: secretarial and accountancy schools, Algeria (Reports 009296), 1974 (Box 386)
  Memo to Robert H. Edwards and Wilbert J. LeMelle, dated April 11, 1974.
  5 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Accounting -- Study and teaching -- Algeria; Public administration -- Study and teaching -- Algeria; Technical assistance -- Algeria; Endowments -- Algeria -- Evaluation
- Terminal evaluation: english language textbook development for secondary schools, Tunisia, (690-0742) (Reports 009297), 1974 (Box 386)
  Memo to Robert H. Edwards and Wilbert J. LeMelle, dated April 30, 1974.
  06900742
  Republic of Tunisia
  English language textbook development for secondary schools.
  English language -- Study and teaching -- Tunisia -- Textbooks; English teachers -- Training of -- Tunisia
- Background to delegated authority grant to CAFRAD (Reports 009298), 1974 (Box 386)
  6 p.
  African Training and Research Centre in Administration for Development
- Environmental development in the Middle East (Reports 009299), 1974 (Box 386)
  11 leaves: table -- 28 cm.
  Science -- Research -- Lebanon; Agriculture -- Research -- Lebanon; Industrialization -- Lebanon
- Thoughts on the character and objective of English language projects in the Middle East and Africa Program (Reports 009300), 1966 (Box 386)
  5 p.
  English language training -- Middle East; English language training -- Africa
- The Arid Lands Agricultural Program, outlook and planning review, observations, implications and suggestions (Reports 009301), 1971 (Box 386)
  28 p.
  Agriculture -- Middle East; Agriculture -- Africa, North
- A program for economic and social development of the Caspian-Mazandaran region of Iran: a discussion paper (Reports 009302), 1963 (Box 386)
  18 leaves + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Central planning -- Iran; Economic development -- Iran; Social planning -- Iran; Rural development -- Iran; Technical assistance -- Iran
- The Ford Foundation program in North Africa: 1961-1971 (Reports 009303) (Box 386)
  [v], 25 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Africa, North; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation
- Safeguarding human rights in Biomedical research (Reports 009304), 1972 (Box 386)
  International Division/Population Program
  L72-136.
  3 p.
  Ford Foundation Series
  Ford Foundation funded research involving human subjects
  Medicine -- Research -- Human rights; Human rights -- Biomedical research
- Implementation of policy statement regarding biomedical research involving patients and volunteers (Reports 009305), 1974 (Box 386)
  3 p. + appendices.
- The Ford Foundation and the WHO expanded program of research, development and research training in human reproduction (Reports 009306), 1972 (Box 386)
  International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean
  Population
- Problems in introducing an evaluation system: the Jamaica experience (Reports 009307), 1970 (Box 386)
  9 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Birth control -- Jamaica
- Recommendations to the Director, Dr. Lenworth Jacobs, M.D. National Family Planning Board, Kingston 5, Jamaica, resulting from visit of May 10-18 (Reports 009308), 1969 (Box 386)
  14 p.
- Observations and recommendations based on my visit to the National Family Planning Board, Kingston, Jamaica over the period September 24-30 (Reports 009309), 1969 (Box 386)
  8 p.
  Birth control clinics -- Jamaica
- Report on consultantship with National Family Planning Board (NFPB), Jamaica, December 30, 1968-January 3 (Reports 009310), 1969 (Box 386)
  4 p.
- Report and recommendations to the Director the National Family Planning Board, period of visit: December 30, 1968-January 3 (Reports 009311), 1969 (Box 386)
  7 p.
- A Seminar on Socio-Economic Research and Training in Agriculture: program and background papers (Reports 009312), 1973 (Box 386)
  Seminar sponsored by the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research at the World Bank, Washington DC. July 27-28, 1973.
  75 p.
  Agriculture
- Formal and nonformal education in educational development: Some issues examined Princeton University (Reports 009313), 1974 (Box 386)
  International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean; International Division/Latin America and the Caribbean
  93 p.
  Education -- Latin America
- Higher education, science and technology in Mexico's economic development: a preliminary study (Reports 009314), 1966 (Box 386)
  International Division/Latin America
  104 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Science -- Research -- Mexico; Technology -- Research -- Mexico; Education, Higher -- Mexico; Economic development -- Mexico; Social planning -- Mexico
- A review of the Ford Foundation's child care assistance policy (Reports 009315), 1980 (Box 386)
  Women's Programs/Operations and Management/Personnel
  78 p.
  Child care -- Policy
- Communicating with communicators: a study of the International Institute of Communications (Reports 009316), 1979 (Box 386)
  Office of Communications/International Division/European and International Affairs
  07400019
  44 p. + annex.
  Communication
- Evaluation of Ford Foundation Grant PA64-434 to the Center for Research on Economic Development, University of Michigan, 1967-1980 (Reports 009317), 1982 (Box 386)
  International Division/Middle East and Africa/Developing Countries Program/West Africa
  06400434
  Regents of the University of Michigan
  Strengthening the Center for Research on Economic Development.
  36 p. + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Economics -- Research -- Africa, West; Economics -- Study and teaching -- Africa, West; Endowments -- United States -- Evaluation
- CRED (Recommendations), Resource Bases and Recruitment (Suggestions) (Reports 009318), 1968 (Box 386)
  Resource bases -- Middle East and Asia
- Evaluation of research produced during the year 1977-78 by CEUR-Buenos Aires (Reports 009319), 1978 (Box 386)
  International Division/Developing Countries Program
  07700525
  25 p.
  City planning; Regional planning
- Observations on the Indonesian cultural scene (Reports 009320), 1977 (Box 386)
  International Division/Asia and the Pacific
  73-805.
  13 p. + attachments.
  Arts -- Indonesia; Cultural preservation -- Indonesia
- Report on my visit to Palembang to evaluate the Population Education Course for SLA teachers, Feb. 22 and 23 (Reports 009321), 1974 (Box 386)
  Developing Countries Program/Asia and the Pacific
  07450301
  Education -- Population; Education, Higher -- Indonesia
- Assessment of the Documentation of the association of African Universities (AAU) (Reports 009322), 1974 (Box 386)
  07200020
  13 p.
  Education, Higher -- Africa; Documentation centres -- Africa
- Report on the Documentation Centre on the AAU in ACCRA based on Travel in Paris and West Africa Feb. 2-28 (Reports 009323), 1974 (Box 386)
  2 p.
- A picture of the population problem in Brazil today (Reports 009324), 1966 (Box 386)
  06600124
  Federal University of Bahia
  23 p. + attachments.
  Population research -- Brazil
- Report on trip to Bahia (Reports 009325), 1965 (Box 386)
  File memo dated June 26, 1965.
  International Division/Office of the Vice President
  Program in reproductive biology and fertility control at the University.
  8 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Birth control clinics -- Brazil -- Evaluation; Human reproduction -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil; Population assistance -- Brazil; Birth control -- Brazil; Education, Higher -- Brazil; Universities and colleges -- Brazil
- Site visit to Federal University of Bahia (Reports 009326), 1974 (Box 386)
  File memo dated October 24, 1974.
  6 leaves + attachment
  Human reproduction -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil; Universities and colleges -- Brazil; Population assistance -- Brazil; Birth control -- Brazil; Education, Higher -- Brazil
- Puebla Project - An analysis of benefits and costs (Reports 009327), 1971 (Box 387)
  06700204
  Agricultural development projects -- Research institutes
- Memorandum: financing international agricultural research institutes (Reports 009328), 1968 (Box 387)
  15 p. + attachments.
  Agricultural development projects; Agriculture -- International cooperation; Agricultural research institutes
- Trip to Southeast Asia (Reports 009329), 1967 (Box 387)
  Agriculture -- International development; Agricultural research institutes
- Visit to Department of Agricultural Economics, UFCe, April 12 (Reports 009330), 1978 (Box 387)
  06900731
  20 p.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Brazil; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Brazil
- Progress and problems of the Master's Degree Program in Agricultural Economics of the Federal University of Ceara (Reports 009331), 1976 (Box 387)
  Title sufficient as abstract.
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Brazil
  Federal University of Ceara
  30 p.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Brazil
- Selecting and evaluating new technology for small farmers in the Central Sertao of Ceara (Reports 009332), 1971 (Box 387)
  27 p.
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Brazil; Farms, Small -- Brazil
- Review of Benin Grant, Francophone Students at Ibadan (Reports 009333), 1976 (Box 387)
  07500435
  Education, Higher -- Benin; Agriculture -- Benin
- Evaluation of Grant to the National University of Nenin in support of Study and Research Program for Beninois students at the University of Ibandan and IITA (Reports 009334), 1978 (Box 387)
  Education, Higher -- Benin
- Report of Consultant, Dr. Assa Ayemou, on visit to University of Benin and Evaluation of the Benin Ibandan - IITA Program (Reports 009335), 1978 (Box 387)
  16 p.
- Advanced International Reporting Fellows Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism: Ford Foundation Seminar February 22-23, 1971. (Reports 009336) (Box 387)
  Includes list: Alumni of the Advanced International Reporting Program, Graduate School of Journalism, Columbia University.
  International Division
  19 p.
  Ford Foundation activities
- Problems of urbanization in Kingston, Jamaica (Reports 009337), 1971 (Box 387)
  Urbanization -- Jamaica; Poor -- Jamaica
- Observations on the situation in Pakistan (Reports 009338), 1971 (Box 387)
  13 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Pakistan; Technical assistance -- Bangladesh; Endowments -- Pakistan -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Bangladesh -- Evaluation
- Pakistan: Mid- (Reports 009339), 1971 (Box 387)
  3 leaves -- 28 cm.
- Social Science Program, Fiscal Year 1969 Budget (Reports 009340), 1968 (Box 387)
  Related Conference
  PAPER Conference (1968 Nov. 6-8: Bogota, Colombia)
  Agricultural development projects -- Latin America
- An annotated bibliography on the history of American Foundations (Reports 009341), 1984 (Box 387)
  Office of the Vice President
  1 v. v(arious pagings) -- 28 cm.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted from access.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- History; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Bibliography; Charities -- United States -- History; Charities -- United States -- Bibliography; Nonprofit organizations -- United States
- Potential for Foundation support to the Fundacion Promotora de Cooperativas (FPC) and the Universidad Centro Americana Jose Simeon Canas (UCA) in El Salvador (Reports 009342), 1974 (Box 387)
  18 p.
  Rural development -- Central America
- Trip to Costa Rica and Guatemala (Reports 009343), 1971 (Box 387)
  11 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Technical assistance -- Costa Rica; Technical assistance -- Guatemala
- Tentative outline for discussions, meetings of Central American urban and regional planners and observers, to be sponsored by the Ford Foundation (Reports 009344), 1968 (Box 387)
  City planning -- Central America; Cities and towns -- Central America
- Palabras explicativas por el arquitecto Mario Martin de Honduras (Reports 009345), 1968 (Box 387)
  36 p.
  Seminar: urban and regional development (San Salvador)
- After one-quarter of a century: An evaluation of the Institute of Social and Economic Research, the University of the West Indies (Reports 009346), 1975 (Box 387)
  Draft, May 1974, copy included.
  65 p.
  Social and economic research
- Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (Reports 009347), 1971
  Memo to Heads, POICs and overseas representatives, dated May 24, 1971.
  2 p. + attachments -- 28 cm.
  Agriculture -- Research -- Developing countries
- Stiftung Volkswagenwerk (The Volkswagen Foundation) (Reports 009348), 1971 (Box 387)
  International Division/European and International Affairs
  Foundations -- Europe
- Program strategy in Central America: science and technology (Reports 009349), 1968 (Box 387)
  Memo to Messrs. Gamble, Bergman, Blair, Coonty, Gonzales, Rubel, Stevenson, Veneaian, and Miss Tanck, August 21, 1968.
  10 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Science -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Central America; Engineering -- Study and teaching (Graduate) -- Research -- Central America; Education (Graduate) -- Central America
- Universidad Metropolitana Caracas (Reports 009350), 1972 (Box 387)
  Education, Higher -- Venezuela
- Social sciences program strategy for Central America (Reports 009351), 1968 (Box 387)
  Social sciences -- Central America
- YORUBA Six-year Project: The June 1976 evaluation: McGill Univ (Reports 009352) (Box 387)
  07000159
  34 p. + appendix.
  Education, Primary -- Nigeria
- YORUBA Six-Year Project: The June 1977 evaluation: McGill Univ (Reports 009353), 1978 (Box 387)
- Adlai E. Stevenson Institute (Reports 009354), 1975 (Box 387)
  United States and International Affairs Program/International Affairs
  07600022
  The Greater Washington Educational Telecommunications Association, Inc.
  Support of management reorganization and national programming.
  15 leaves + attachment -- 28 cm.
  International affairs -- Study and teaching
- Humanities, humanists, and values (Reports 009355), 1977 (Box 387)
  Education and Research/Public Policy and Social Organization
  10 p. + attachments.
  Humanities -- Foundation work
- Informe del Viaje del Lic. Rodrigo A. Medellin, Al Indide: Ciudad de Lima, del 26 de Febrero al 10 de Marzo de (Reports 009356), 1973 (Box 387)
  07100569
  Education -- Research -- Peru
- Informe del Doctor Pablo Latapi Sobre las Actividades de Investigacion en el INIPM (Reports 009357), 1972 (Box 387)
  15 p. + appendix.
- Consultation re a proposed program of assistance to the MED Educational Research Center: University of Pittsburgh (Reports 009358), 1971 (Box 387)
- The Overseas Development Council: an evaluation for the Ford and Rockefeller Foundations, 1982 (Reports 009359) (Box 387)
  08000461; 07900373.
  68 leaves.
  Economic assistance, American -- Developing countries
- An evaluation of the accelerated cereal projects in Tunisia and in Algeria and the related Ford Foundation grants to CIMMYT (Reports 009360), 1973 (Box 388)
  Pa68-848
  44 p. -- 28 cm.
  Agricultural development projects -- Africa, North; Cereal products -- Agriculture -- Africa, North; Agriculture -- Africa, North
- Brazil Northeast Research Project: Program of Development of Resource Research center for the Semi-Arid Zone (Reports 009361), 1975 (Box 388)
  07300725
  Institute of Agronomic Research
  Agricultural development projects -- Brazil
- Brazil Northeast Research Project: Program for Sorghum/Millet research (Reports 009362), 1975 (Box 388)
  09350725
  10 p.
- Terminal report on the Ford Foundation agricultural production technology project on Sorghum and Millets for the Semi-Arid Region of Northeast Brazil (Reports 009363), 1978 (Box 388)
- Proposed approaches to programming on ethnic conflict (Reports 009365), undated (Box 388)
  Pa76-811.
  Publication date unknown. Records more than ten years are open for research.
  Ethnic relations; Human rights
- On the political and cultural consequences of the expulsion of fourteen Argentine Science professors by the Chilean Government (Reports 009366), 1969 (Box 388)
  Human rights -- Chile
- On human rights and U.S. Government policy (Reports 009367), 1977 (Box 388)
  Pa76-811
  9 p.
  Human rights -- United States
- Trip to Western Europe, March 1-7, 1977, concerning East-West Conferences on European Security (Reports 009368) (Box 388)
  10 p. + appendices.
  European security
- Access to information: an international problem (Reports 009369), 1977 (Box 388)
  25 p. + attachments.
  Freedom of information -- Developing countries; Communication -- Developing countries; Freedom of the press -- Developing countries
- A proposed Foundation-wide program on immigration and refugees, Nov. 9 (Reports 009370), 1979 (Box 388)
  07690811
  The Ford Foundation
  Emigration and immigration; Refugees; Human rights
- Ethnic conflict: focusing the research program (Reports 009371), 1978 (Box 388)
  Ethnic rights; Human rights
- Argentina (Reports 009372), 1976 (Box 388)
  Human rights -- Argentina; Refugees -- Argentina
- Refugee situation in Argentina (Reports 009373), 1976 (Box 388)
- Ethnic conflict policy studies: a concept paper. (Reports 009374), 1979 (Box 388)
  Education and Public Policy (EPP)/National Affairs
  11 p.
  Ethnic relations
- Recent European visit (Reports 009375), 1978 (Box 388)
  Human rights -- Europe
- Trip to Latin America (Reports 009376), 1976 (Box 388)
  49 p.
  Human rights -- Latin America
- The Republic of South Africa (Reports 009377), 1976 (Box 388)
  Human rights -- South Africa
- South and Southern Africa refugee situation-available and potential sources of assistance (Reports 009378), 1977 (Box 388)
  34 p.
  Human rights -- South Africa; Refugees -- South Africa
- Derechos humanos: sugerencias sobre prioridades para investigacion y reflexion (Reports 009379), 1977 (Box 388)
  Ford Foundation
  20 p. + attachments -- 28 cm
  Human rights -- Latin America; Social justice -- Latin America
- Caribbean Human Rights Continuation Committee and Caribbean Human Rights and Legal Aid Company (CAHURLAC) (Reports 009380), 1979 (Box 388)
  11 p. + attachments.
- Human rights resources Project: a report of the findings in Phase 1 and a consideration of whether, and if so how, to proceed to Phase 2 (Reports 009381), 1979 (Box 388)
  117 p.
  Human rights
- Preliminary thoughts on the Funders meetings (Reports 009382), 1980 (Box 388)
- Population and family planning communicaitons need for a Spanish speaking training center: comments on a proposal from Costa Rica (Reports 009383), 1970 (Box 388)
  Prepared for Mr. John S. Nagel [and] Dr. William Moore. --T.p.
  07200437
  University of Costa Rica
  Latin American program of communication training for family planning.
  6 leaves + appendices: tables -- 28 cm.
  Communication in birth control -- Costa Rica; Birth control -- Study and teaching -- Costa Rica; Population assistance -- Costa Rica
- Kenya: developing a family planning communication plan for 1970 (Reports 009384)
  Birth control -- Kenya; Population assistance -- Kenya
- Harish Chandra Mathur State University of Public Administration: evaluation of grant (Reports 009385), 1971 (Box 388)
  06700284
  15 p.
  Public administration -- India
- Report and assessment of the Harish Chandra Mathur State Institute of Public Administration (Reports 009386), 1969 (Box 388)
- Some thoughts after 10 years of Ford Foundation work in Europe (Reports 009387), 1980 (Box 388)
  6 leaves -- 28 cm.
  International relations -- Research; Endowments -- Europe -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management
- On building capacity in agricultural research management for small and medium holders in Pakistan (Reports 009388), 1980 (Box 388)
  Agriculture -- Research -- Pakistan
- Beyond the Green Revolution (Reports 009389), 1983 (Box 388)
  "This paper criticises common views of the green revolution in South Asia and argues for enabling small farmers and landless labourers to gain command over more resources. Opportunities are identified in water reform on canal irrigation, land reform when
  26 p.
  Green Revolution -- India; Rural poor -- India; Irrigation -- India; Agricultural research -- India; Natural resources, Communal -- India
- Social forestry, wood gasifiers and irrigation: a synergistic relationship (Reports 009390), 1983 (Box 388)
  Power resources -- India
- Community participation: a management perspective on obstacles and options (Reports 009391), 1980 (Box 388)
  Community development -- Philippines